Guide to the Historic Photographs and Drawings Collection Photo.002
New York University Archives
- Series I: Oversized Photographs and Drawings
  - NYU Basketball Dinner at NYU Athletic Club 1933-34, 1933-1934; 20.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Football Dinner at the Biltmore- December 11, 1930, 20.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: surface dirt, planar distortion/curling, white writing in Verso: heavy surface dirt, paper label affixed, writing in pencil, writing in black pen, stamp in red ink, small breaks along edges Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Annual NYU Letter Club Dinner in Honor of 1928 Football Team- March 5, 1929, 20.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: planar distortion/curling, heavy surface dirt, writing in white from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, yellowing/discoloration, three stamps in purple ink, writings in pencil. Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Kappa Sigma Annual Dinner for New York University- March 26, 1913, 19x11.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size:18.5x11 Mounting size:19x11.5 Recto: some yellowing/discoloration, writing in white from negative Verso: two writings in pencil, writing in black pen, black fingerprints, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Class of 1930 University Heights- First Reunion Zeta Psi Club- May 16, 1936, 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: surface dirt, writing in white from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Annual Norris Dinner NYU Nu Epsilon Phi Gamma Delta- May 9, 1922, 16.5x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo size:15.5x10 Mounting size: 16.5x11 Recto: yellowing/discoloration, writing in pencil, white writing from negative, bottom left corner missing from mounting Verso: heavy surface dirt key to photograph included Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Anniversary Dinner of NYU Chapter of Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternity- June 6, 1968, 14x10 black and white photograph Recto: breaks in photograph, writing in white from negative, curling/planar distortion Verso: pencil mark, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - NYU Omicron Kappa Upsilon- Omega Chapter Annual Dinner- May 22, 1957, 19x10 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, writing in white from negative, some surface dirt Verso: yellow marks, some surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Alpha Kappa Psi Fraternity- NYU Chapter- December 5, 1967, 20x10 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion Verso: red mark Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - First Annual Dinner- NYU Beta Gamma Sigma- December 2, 1933, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: planar distortion/curling, tearing along edges, some pieces missing from edges, white writing from negative Verso: writing in red pencil, heavy surface dirt, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner, n.d.; 15x10.5 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner, n.d.; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: curling, planar distortion Verso: heavy surface dirt, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner, n.d.; 20x13 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 20x12 Mounting size: 20x13 Recto: cracking on surface of photograph, heavy surface dirt, Verso: heavy surface dirt, dark stains, writing in pencil Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner, n.d.; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: breaks (from rolling) Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, breaks, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner, n.d.; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: white label with purple ink, heavy surface dirt, tear along right side, bends at corners Verso: red pencil, stamp in purple ink, heavy surface dirt, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Unidentified NYU Dinner, n.d.; 22x14 black and white photograph Recto: heavy surface dirt, white writing from negative, tears along edges, bends at corners Verso: extremely heavy surface dirt, writings in pencil, stamp in black ink, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - New York University Testimonial Dinners to NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown- May 3, 1933, 22x14 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: heavy surface dirt, writing in white from negative, rippling along edges, bottom right corner missing Verso: cracks and breaks along back surface, rippling along edges, heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - A Little Dinner to "Porky" By a Few Friends at NYU- New York Alumni Club- December 29, 1936, 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion Verso: yellowing, heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Dinner for NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown- 15th Anniversary- November 8, 1926, 23.5x12.5 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: heavy surface dirt, tears along top edge, white writing from negative Verso: yellowing, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Negative of Dinner for NYU Chancellor E.E. Brown- 15th Anniversary- November 8, 1926, 8x10 black and white negative (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Friendship Luncheon Tendered for NYU Dean John William Withers- May 14, 1938, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: heavy surface dirst, tears and breaks along edges, pressure adhesive along edge Verso: heavy surface dirt, writing in pencil, pressure adhesive Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - Tendered to Dr. Frank H. Sommer by the NYU Law Alumni Association for his 25th Anniversary as Dean- January 30, 1941, 20x12 black and white photograph 5 copies of this item exist Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 11)
  - 20th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU- December 3, 1932, 18x10.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo and mounting size are the same Recto: small scratches, writing in white from negative Verso: writing in pencil, yellowing, break in the mounting Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 18th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU- December 13, 1930, 20.5x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt/fingerprints, curling/planar distortion Verso: surface dirt/fingerprints, writing in red pencil, Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 19th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU- December 5, 1931, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt/fingerprints, curling/planar distortion, tattered edges, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt/fingerprints, writing in red pencil, stamp in purple ink Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 15th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU- December 17, 1927, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt/fingerprints, curling/planar distortion, tattered edges, white writing from negative Verso: surface dirt/fingerprints, writing in red pencil, stamp in blue ink Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 16th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU- December 15, 1928, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt/fingerprints, curling/planar distortion, tears at edges, white writing from negative, writing in pencil Verso: heavy surface dirt/fingerprints, writing in red pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 13th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU- December 19, 1925, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt/fingerprints, curling/planar distortion, tattered edges, white writing from negative, bottom right corner missing, break in center of photo Verso: heavy surface dirt/fingerprints, writing in red pencil, stamp in blue ink Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 14th Annual Dinner of Delta Mu Delta of NYU- December 11, 1926, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt/fingerprints, curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative, top right corner is bent Verso: surface dirt/fingerprints, two writings in red pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Annual Dinner of NYU Law School Alumni Association- March 2, 1940, 22.5x14 this item is broken into 4 pieces Recto: yellowing/discoloration, tears along edges, pressure adhesive repairing tears, writing in white from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, pressure adhesives to repair multiple tears Condition: Poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 44th Annual Dinner of the NYU Law School Alumni- January 14, 1928, 19x12 black and white photograph Broken into two pieces Recto: heavy surface dirt, white writing from negative, yellowing/discoloration Verso: heavy surface dirt Condition: Poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 49th Annual Dinner of the Alumni Association of NYU Law School- February 9, 1935, 20x12 black and white photographs Recto: break along surface of photo, planar distortion/curling, writing in white from negative, some surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt, writings in pencil, stamp in purple ink Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 70th Annual NYU Law Alumni Association Dinner- March 19, 1958, 10x8 mounted black and white photograph Photo and mounting are the same size Verso: strips of pressure adhesive Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 46th Annual Dinner- NYU Law School- January 31, 1931, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: heavy surface dirt, extreme curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in red ink Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Annual Dinner for the NYU School of Law Alumni Association- March 9, 1936, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative, crease along right side Verso: writings in pencil, stamp in purple ink, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 51st Annual Dinner NYU Law School of Law Alumni Association- March 16, 1937, 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamps in purple ink, writings in pencol, deposits from adhesive, yellowing/discoloration Condition: both are good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 48th Annual Dinner of the Alumni Association for NYU Law School- January 31, 1933, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: top right corner bent, surface dirt, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink, black fingerprints Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Dinner Given by the Board of Directors of the NYU Law School Alumni Association in honor of Dean Sommer- May 27, 1943, 14x11 black and white photograph 3 copies of this item exist Recto: planar distortion/curling, names of those in attendance, some surface dirt Verso: some surface dirt, stamp in black ink Condition: good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 75th Annual NYU Law Alumni Association Dinner- April 17, 1963, 10.5x8.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo and mounting size are the same Verso: strips of pressure adhesive Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Annual Dinner of the Alumni Association of NYU College Dentistry- April 3, 1936, 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: white writing from negative Verso: writing in pencil, stamp in black ink, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 25th Anniversary Dinner- Class of 1914 NYU College of Dentistry- April 28, 1939, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: bend on top right corner, bottom left corner missing, surface dirt/fingerprints, white writing from negative, rippling along edges, planar distortion/curling Verso: heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - NYU College of Dentistry Alumni Association Geoge Washington Hotel November 19, 1937 (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Medical Prepatory Banquet- April 14, 1918, 17x11.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo and mounting are the same size Recto: bottom right corner is broken and has been reattached using clear pressure adhesive, extreme discoloration/fading, white writing from negative Verso: large water(?) stain, deposits from adhesive, flaking of mounting Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - NYU College of Medicine- Class of 1922- May 1, 1937, 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative, tears along the edges, heavy surface dirt Verso: heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 25th Anniversary of the Class of 1912- NYU College of Dentistry- May 20, 1937, 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: heavy surface dirt, curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks Condition: good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 10th Anniversary Class of 1927 NYU College of Dentistry- April 29, 1937, 20x10 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative, some surface dirt along the edges Verso: writing in black pen, black marks, heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 25th Anniversary Dinner- Class of 1912 NYU School of Medicine- May 8, 1937, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, some surface dirt, black fingerprints, white writing from negative Verso: writing in pencil, stamp in blue ink, surface dirt, Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 25th Anniversary Dinner Class of 1907 NYU Medical College- February 27, 1932, 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: rippling along edges, curling/planar distortion, Verso: marks in red pencil, heavy surface dirt, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - NYU College of Dentistry Alumni and Faculty Banquet in honor of Dean A. T. Newman- October 25, 1929, 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: surface dirt, white writing from negative, curling/planar distortion Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks, some small tears along edges Condition: Good for both (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 13th Anniversary Class of 1915 NYU College of Medicine- May 5, 1945, 20x10 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, curling/planar distortion, bottom left corner is bent and broken, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 20th Anniversary Dinner for Class of 1919 NYU College of Medicine- March 29, 1939, 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: some curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, large black mark Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 18th Graduate Course in Surgery Dinner NYU- May 19, 1938, 20x10 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative, crease at center Verso: surface dirt, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 30th Anniversary Reunion Class of 1914 NYU College of Dentistry- May 17, 1944, 20x10 black and white photograph Recto: some surface dirt, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, yellowing, fingerprints Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - 20th Anniversary Reunion Dinner- NYU Dental College class of 1914- April 20, 1934, 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - NYU College of Dentistry- April 16, 1937, 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: some curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative, bottom left corner bent and broken Verso: heavy surface dirt Condition: Good for both (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Annual Dinner for NYU Arts and Engineering Alumni- February 5, 1937, 20x12 black and white photograph 2 copies of this item exist Recto: surface dirt, white writing from negative Verso: heavy surface dirt, black marks Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Class of 1933 NYU School of Arts and Engineering- May 14, 1938, 20x12 black and white photograph 6 copies of this item exist Recto: curling/planar distortion, white writing from negative, rippling along edges Verso: some surface dirt Condition: Good for all (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Negative of Annual Dinner of the NYU Engineering Alumni- February 11, 1911, 10.5x8.5 black and white negative Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - NYU College of Dentistry Class of 1928- Collage Photograph, 24x17 black and white photograph collage Recto: yellowing/discoloration, printing in black ink, tears along edges Verso: yellowing/extreme discoloration, heavy surface dirt, clear pressure adhesive repairing breaks and tears Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - NYU College of Dentistry Class of 1916- Collage Photograph, 20x20 mounted black and white collage photograph Recto: large pieces are missing or broken, yellowing/discoloration, heavy surface dirt Verso: yellowing, heavy surface dirt Condition: Poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 12)
  - Unidentified NYU Student Photo, circa 1910; 14x11 black and white photograph Recto: multiple pieces missing, tears along the edges, yellowing Verso: writings in pencil, mark in blue pencil, heavy surface dirt, heavy surface dirt Condition: Poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Ringling Brother's and Barnum and Bailey Combined Circus, 1937; 20x12 black and white photograph Recto: curling/planar distortion, bends at corners, curling/planar distortion Verso: heavy surface dirt, stamp in purple ink, black fingerprints Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Meeting of the New York Historical Society, held in the Gothic Chapel of the old NYU building, c.1850., circa 1850; 19x13 mounted black and white print Recto: two mounted images and one label, yellowing Verso: Pressure adhesive holding prints in place Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - James Bryant Conant, President of Harvard; James Rowland Angell, President of Yale, Harold Willis Dodds, President of Princeton at NYU- June 13, 1934, 16.5x15 mounted, autographed black and white photograph Recto: autographs in black pen, yellowing, some flaking at edges of mounting Verso: mounted letter affixed to the verso with pressure adhesive and clear plastic sheet protector, yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Unidentified Attendees at Event Given by Mrs. Anderson of the NYU Dean's Office, 16.5x13.5 mounted black and white photograph Photo size: 14x11 Mounting size: 16.5x13.5 Recto: stains from adhesive, yellowing Verso: brown stains from liquid(?), writing in pencil, yellowing Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Event for WCBS-TV Award Presented to NYU- September 27, 1966, 14x11 mounted black and white photograph Photo and mounting are the same size Recto: wrinkling, bends in photograph, small tears, some adhesive deposits Verso: pieces missing from the mounting, yellowing Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - NYU Washington Square College Bulletin- May 1, 1941, 20x15 newspaper General: extreme yellowing/discoloration Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Map of NY Harlem Quadrangle, US Geological Survey Map 1873- from 1932, 24x19 printed map with blue ink 4 copies of this item exist General: extreme yellowing/discoloration, multiple breaks and tears Condition: Poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Hand drawn Map of NY Harlem Quadrangle with notes regarding land ownership c.1873 (?), 36x23 black printing on fiber paper Recto: severe yellowing/discoloration, very crispy, multiple tears and breaks, pieces missing, writing in pencil and pen, multiple wrinkles Verso: severe yellowing/discoloration, multiple tears and breaks Condition: Poor (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Architectural Drawing of Grey Art Gallery at NYU from William C Shopsin AIA & Giorgio Cavaglieri Faia Associated Architects- Basement Plan, circa 1974; 18x14 black and white print Recto: planar distortion/curling, print in black ink, some tears Verso: planar distortion/curling, some tears Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Traced Map of NY Harlem Quadrangle with notes regarding land ownership c.1873 (?), 20x16 pencil drawing on tracing paper Recto: wrinkled, planar distortion, some yellowing, writing in pencil, multiple tears and breaks Condition: Fair (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Drawing of Washington Square Arch, n.d.; 25x19 black and white print on fiber paper Recto: yellowing, lines from folding, some surface dirt Verso: thin brown lines Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Architectural Drawing of Grey Art Gallery at NYU from William C Shopsin AIA & Giorgio Cavaglieri Faia Associated Architects- Ground Floor Plan, circa 1974; 18x14 black and white print Recto: planar distortion/curling, print in black ink, some tears Verso: planar distortion/curling, some tears Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Drawings of NYU Washington Square East Elevation and Washington Place Elevation by William C Shopsin AIA & Giorgio Cavaglieri Faia Associated Architects, circa 1974; 18x14 black and white print Recto: planar distortion/curling, print in black ink, some tears Verso: planar distortion/curling, some tears Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Drawing of Grey Art Gallery NYU by Tesla, 1974; 18x14 black and white print Recto: planar distortion/curling, print in black ink, some tears Verso: planar distortion/curling, some tears Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 13)
  - Facsimile of George Washington's Inaugural Address, n.d.; 16x14 fascimile/reproduction, black ink on what appears to be tea-stained fiber paper Recto: black printing Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Facsimile of First Patent of America, n.d.; 16x14 fascimile/reproduction, black ink on what appears to be tea-stained fiber paper Recto: black printing Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Facsimile of Mayflower Contract, n.d.; 16x14 fascimile/reproduction, black ink on what appears to be tea-stained fiber paper Recto: black printing Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Facsimile of United States Constitution, n.d.; 14x16 fascimile/reproduction, black ink on what appears to be tea-stained fiber paper Recto: black printing Condition: Good 4 copies of this item exist (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Fascimile of the United States Declaration of Independence, 14x16 fascimile/reproduction, black ink on what appears to be tea-stained fiber paper Recto: black printing Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted Display Label- "Photographs by Jerry M. Robinson" from "New Yorkers In the Hall of Fame for Great Americans" NYU Exhibit, 9x3.75 mounted white paper Recto: black printing, some stains and tears at edges Verso: writing in pencil, small holes Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted Display Label- "New Yorkers In the Hall of Fame for Great Americans- Part I: Contributors to the Arts and Sciences" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 30x8 mounted white paper Recto: writing in black paint, some surface dirt, yellow stains, small holes at four corners Verso: skinning of mounting, stains and deposits from adhesive Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)
  - Mounted Display Label- "New Yorkers In the Hall of Fame for Great Americans- Part II: Leaders in Public Affairs, Social Welface and Education" NYU Exhibit, 1976; 30x8 mounted white paper Recto: writing in black paint, some surface dirt, yellow stains, small holes at four corners Verso: skinning of mounting, surface dirt, writing in pencil Condition: Good (Map-case 8, Drawer 14)